(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T00:45:17.182975",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
AZKi 8th Birthday Live
AZKi
AZKi 8th Birthday Live Crossover 平成 vs 令和 アニソン歌合戦
AZKi 8th Birthday Live Crossover: Heisei vs. Reiwa Anison Song Battle
IRyS / 音乃瀬奏
IRyS / Otonose Kanade
みんな、こんあずき！
Hello, everyone! Kon-AZKi!
今日はAZKi 8thバースデーライブ「CROSS OVER」
Today is AZKi's 8th Birthday Live, "CROSS OVER"...
平成・令和アニソン歌合戦にお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Heisei vs Reiwa Anime Song Battle! Thank you all for coming!
今回は、平成赤チームと令和青チームの
This time, we are split into Heisei Red Team...
2チームに分かれて、アニソンで歌合戦をやっていきまーす！
...and Reiwa Blue Team for an anime song battle!
今回ゲストのみんなも
Our guest performers as well...
それぞれのチームに分かれて参戦してくれます！
...will join by splitting into their respective teams!
ハッシュタグは、「#AZKi生誕ライブ2026」
The hashtag is "#AZKi生誕ライブ2026"...
こちらこちら！
...right over here!
赤チームここが良かったよとか
Like, "This part of the Red Team was great!"...
青チームここが美しかったよとか、たくさんポストお願いします！
...or "This part of the Blue Team was beautiful!" Please post a lot!
そして、サムネイルにも書いてありますが
Also, as written on the thumbnail...
新衣装のお披露目と！
...there's a new outfit reveal!
重大告知もあるので
And we have a major announcement...
楽しみにしててください！
...so please look forward to it!
ということで！
With that said...
みんな、盛り上がる準備はいいかー！？
...everyone, are you ready to get hyped?!
おおー！それでは
Awesome! Well then...
平成・令和アニソン歌合戦、開幕です！
...Heisei vs Reiwa Anime Song Battle, let's begin!
まずは平成赤チーム
First up is the Heisei Red Team.
アイリス
IRyS.
楽曲は
Her song is...
アニメ「新世紀エヴァンゲリオン」より、すべての始まりとなる一曲
From the anime "Neon Genesis Evangelion," the song where it all began...
「残酷な天使のテーゼ」
"A Cruel Angel's Thesis"!
続いて令和青チーム
Next is the Reiwa Blue Team.
音乃瀬奏
Otonose Kanade.
楽曲は
Her song is...
「シン・エヴァンゲリオン劇場版」より、すべてを終わりに導く曲
From "Evangelion: 3.0+1.0 Thrice Upon a Time," the song that leads everything to its end...
「One Last Kiss」
"One Last Kiss"!
時代を超えて交差する２つのメロディ
Two melodies intersecting across eras.
２曲続けてどうぞ！
Please enjoy these two songs back-to-back!
残酷な天使のように
Like a cruel angel...
少年よ 神話になれ
...young boy, become a legend!
蒼い風がいま 胸のドアを叩いても
Even if a clear blue wind knocks at the door to your heart...
私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
...you are merely gazing at me and smiling.
そっとふれるもの もとめることに夢中で
You're so intent on seeking out something gently touching...
運命さえまだ知らない いたいけな瞳
...with such innocent eyes, unaware of your fate.
だけどいつか気付くでしょう その背中には
But someday I think you'll find out that on your back...
遥か未来めざすための 羽根があること
...are wings meant for heading toward the far-off future.
残酷な天使のテーゼ 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
The cruel angel's thesis will soon take flight through the window...
ほとばしる熱いパトスで 思い出を裏切るなら
...with surging, hot pathos. If you betray your memories...
この宇宙を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
...embracing this sky and shining, young boy, become a legend!
ずっと 眠ってる
You have been sleeping forever...
私の愛の揺りかご
...in the cradle of my love.
あなただけが 夢の使者に
Only you will face the morning...
呼ばれる朝がくる
...when you're summoned by a messenger of dreams.
細い首筋を
The moonlight shines...
月あかりが映してる
...on your slender neck.
世界中の時を止めて
I want to stop time throughout the world...
閉じ込めたいけど保存
...and lock you away, but...
もしもふたり逢えたことに
If there is indeed a meaning...
意味があるなら保存
...to our chance meeting,
私はそう
Then I am, yes...
自由を知るためのバイブル
...the bible that teaches you of freedom.
残酷な天使のテーゼ
A cruel angel's thesis...
悲しみがそしてはじまる
...and then, sorrow begins.
抱きしめた命のかたち
The shape of the life you embraced...
その夢に目覚めたとき
...when you awaken to that dream.
誰よりも光を放つ
Shine brighter than anyone else!
少年よ 神話になれ
Young boy, rise to become a legend!
人は愛をつむぎながら保存
People weave together love...
歴史をつくる
...to create history.
女神なんてなれないまま
Unable to become a goddess,
私は生きる
I will live on.
残酷な天使のテーゼ
A cruel angel's thesis...
窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
...will soon fly high from the window.
ほとばしる熱いパトスで
With an overflowing, burning passion...
思い出を裏切るなら
...if you must betray your memories,
この宇宙を抱いて輝く
Shine, holding this universe in your arms!
少年よ 神話になれ
Young boy, rise to become a legend!
初めてのルーブルは
My first time at the Louvre
なんてことはなかったわ
was really no big deal,
私だけのモナリザ
because my very own Mona Lisa
もうとっくに出会ってたから
is someone I met long ago.
初めてあなたを見た
The day I first laid eyes on you,
あの日の動き出した歯車
the gears began to turn.
止められない喪失の予感
An unstoppable premonition of loss...
もういっぱいあるけど
We already have so many,
もう一つ増やしましょう
but let's add one more.
(Can you give me one last kiss?)
忘れたくないこと
Something I don't want to forget.
Oh oh oh oh oh...
忘れたくないこと
Something I don't want to forget.
Oh oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
「写真は苦手なんだ」
"I don't like being photographed."
でもそんなものはいらないわ
But I don't need such things,
あなたが焼きついたまま
because you are burnt forever
私の心のプロジェクター
onto the projector screen of my heart.
寂しくないふりしてた
I was pretending I wasn't lonely.
まあ、そんなのお互い様か
Well, I guess we're both in the same boat.
誰かを求めることは保存
Yearning for someone
即ち傷つくことだった
simply meant getting hurt.
Oh, can you give me one last kiss?
燃えるようなキスをしよう
Let's share a kiss as hot as fire,
忘れたくても
so passionately that even if I wanted to,
忘れられないほど
I won't be able to forget it.
Oh oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
Oh oh oh oh...
もう分かっているよ この世の終わりでも
I already know, even if it's the end of the world,
年をとっても 忘れられない人
even if I grow old, you're the one I can't forget.
Oh oh oh oh...
忘れられない人
The one I can't forget
Oh oh oh oh...
忘れられない人
The one I can't forget
I love you more than you'll ever know
Oh oh oh oh...
忘れられない人
The one I can't forget
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
忘れられない人
The one I can't forget
I love you more than you'll ever know
吹いていった風の後を
Chasing after the breeze
追いかけた眩しい午後
that blew by, one dazzling afternoon
AZKi 8th Birthday Live Crossover!
平成赤チーム、常闇トワ！
Heisei Red Team: Tokoyami Towa!
楽曲はアニメ「けいおん！」より、
The song, from the anime "K-On!",
ガールズバンド旋風を巻き起こしたクールなロックナンバー「Don't say "lazy"」！
is the cool rock number that kicked off a girls' band boom: "Don't say 'lazy'"!
続いて令和青チーム、響咲リオナ！
Next up, Reiwa Blue Team: Isaki Riona!
楽曲はアニメ「ぼっち・ざ・ろっく！」より、
Her song, from the anime "Bocchi the Rock!",
令和のバンドアニメの代表曲「星座になれたら」！
is the representative Reiwa band anime song: "If I Could Be a Constellation"!
時代を超えて響き渡るガールズバンドの系譜、
The lineage of girls' bands echoing across eras...
2曲続けてどうぞ！
Enjoy both songs back-to-back!
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because truthfully, I'm crazy!
白鳥たちはそう
Even swans, you know,
見えないとこでバタ足するんです<
paddle their feet where they can't be seen.
本能に従順 忠実
True to my instincts, loyal and faithful,
翻弄も重々承知
fully aware of being toyed with.
前途洋々だし…
I've got a bright future, after all...
だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
So, that's why I take a rest sometimes.
この目でしっかり見定めて
I'll ascertain it carefully with these eyes,
行き先地図上マークして
and mark my destination on the map.
近道あればそれが王道
If there's a shortcut, that's the royal road,
はしょれる翼もあれば上等
and having wings to skip ahead is even better!
ヤバ 爪割れた
Oh no, I broke a nail!
グルーで補修した
But I fixed it with glue.
それだけでなんか達成感
Just that somehow gives me a sense of achievement.
大事なのは自分 かわいがること
The most important thing is to pamper yourself.
自分を愛さなきゃ 他人も愛せない
You have to love yourself to love anyone else!
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because truthfully, I'm crazy!
能ある鷹はそう
A skilled hawk, you know,
見えないとこにピック隠すんです
hides its pick where it can't be seen.
想像に一生懸命
My imagination is working hard,
現実としては絶体絶命
though reality is a desperate situation.
発展途中だし…
I'm still growing, after all...
だから
Which is why...
だから不意にピッチ外れるんです
Which is why I might suddenly go off pitch
その目に映らないだけだって
Even though it's not in front of your eyes
やる気はメーター振り切って
My motivation is off the charts
いつでも全力で夢見て
Always dreaming with all my might
その分全力で眠って
And sleeping with all my might as well
ヤリ ちょい痩せた 調子づいて喰った
Awesome, I lost a bit of weight, so I happily ate
それだけでなんで？敗北感
And just because of that, why do I feel defeated?
すかさずに目標 下方修正して
Without hesitation, I lower my expectations
柔軟に臨機応変 七変化が勝ち
Flexible, adaptable, the chameleon wins
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because truthfully, I'm crazy!
孔雀たちはそう
Just like how peacocks, you know
ここぞというとき美を魅せるんです
Show off their beauty when the time is right
五臓六腑 満身 邁進
Struggling ahead with body and soul
願望は痩身麗人
Wishing to be a slim and beautiful woman
誘惑多発だし...
There are so many temptations, after all...
だからやけに意志砕けちゃうんです
Which is why my willpower easily crumbles
ヤバ まさか赤点！？いや ギリクリア！
Crap, is that a failing grade!? Ah, barely cleared!
それだけでなんて全能感
Just because of that, why do I feel so almighty?
大事なのは自分 認めてくこと
The most important thing is to accept yourself
自分を許さなきゃ他人も許せない
If you don't forgive yourself, you can't forgive others
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because truthfully, I'm crazy!
白鳥たちはそう
Just like how swans, you know
見えないとこでバタ足するんです
Paddle their feet where they can't be seen
本能に順従忠実
Faithfully obedient to instinct
翻弄も重々承知
Fully aware that we're easily swayed
前途洋々だし...
We have a bright future, after all...
だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
Which is why we take a break sometimes
星座になれたら
[Title: If I Could Be a Constellation]
もうすぐ時計は6時
It's almost six o'clock on the clock
もうそこに一番星
And there is already the first star
影を踏んで
Stepping on the shadows
夜に紛れたくなる帰り道
On my way home, wanting to dissolve into the night
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I search
一つしかない星
There is only one star
何億光年 離れたところから
From billions of light-years away
あんなに輝く
Shining so brightly
いいな 君は みんなから愛されて
Must be nice, you are loved by everyone
「いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ」
“No, I've always been all alone”
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
A starry night, a fleeting wish
きらめいて ゆらめいて 震えてるシグナル
Sparkling, swaying, a trembling signal
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
空見上げて 指を差されるような
Looking up at the sky, as if being pointed at
つないだ線 解かないで
Don't undo the line that connects us
僕がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzling I might be
もうすぐ時計は8時
The clock will soon strike eight
夜空に満天の星
The starry sky is filled with stars
何億光年 離れたところにはもうないかもしれない
Billions of light-years away, they might not even be there anymore
月が綺麗で
The moon is so beautiful
泣きそうになるのは
and I feel like crying
いつの日にか
because someday,
別れが来るから
a farewell will come.
君と集まって星座になれたら
If only I could gather with you and become a constellation
彗星みたい 流れるひとりごと
Like a comet, a passing soliloquy
消えていく残像は真夜中のプリズム
The fading afterimage is a midnight prism
君と集まって星座になれたら
If only I could gather with you and become a constellation
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
If my ardent wish could reach someone
変われるかな 夜の淵を
Could I change? As I trace
なぞるような こんな僕でも
the edges of the night, even for someone like me.
遥か彼方 僕らは出会ってしまった
We met far, far away
カルマだから 何度も出会ってしまうよ
It's karma, so we'll meet again and again
雲の隙間で
In the gaps of the clouds
君と集まって星座になれたら
If only I could gather with you and become a constellation
夜広げて 描こう絵空事
Let's spread out the night and draw our pipe dreams
暗闇を照らすような 満月じゃなくても
Even if it's not a full moon that lights up the darkness
だから集まって星座になりたい
That's why I want to gather with you and become a constellation
色とりどりの光 放つような
Like emitting colorful lights
つないだ線 解かないよ
I won't undo the line that connects us
君がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzling you might be
AZKi 8th Birthday Live CROSSOVER 平成 vs 令和 アニソン歌合戦
AZKi 8th Birthday Live: CROSSOVER! Heisei vs. Reiwa Anime Song Battle!
平成赤チーム、ロボ子さん！
Heisei Red Team: Roboco-san!
楽曲は、アニメ「円盤皇女ワるきゅーレ」より、ラブコメから生まれた儚い名曲「Agape」！
Her song is "Agape" from "UFO Ultramaiden Valkyrie"—a fleeting masterpiece born of romantic comedy!
続いて令和青チーム！
Next up, the Reiwa Blue Team!
水宮枢！
Minamiya Su!
楽曲は、令和版アニメ「うる星やつら」より、夜の街を駆け抜けるダンスチューン「トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ」！
Her song is "Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous" from the Reiwa-era "Urusei Yatsura"—a dance tune that speeds through the night!
宇宙から届いた2つのラブソング、2曲続けてどうぞ！
Here are two love songs sent from space, back to back. Please enjoy!
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear you wherever you are
君がくれる Agape
The agape you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
With all my strength, I dive!
みつめる 触れあう その時
When we gaze at and touch each other,
愛は二人を試している
love is testing the two of us.
Time is now
この世の果てまで
To the very end of this world...
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear you
君がくれる Agape
The Agape you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
Dive with all your might!
信じる 応える その瞬間
Believing, responding, at that instant...
愛が 僕らを ひとつにする
Love brings us together as one.
Time is now
どこまでも生きて
Let's live on, no matter how far...
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear you
君がくれる Agape
The Agape you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
Dive with all your might!
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear you
君がくれる Agape
The Agape you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
Dive with all your might!
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear you
君がくれる Agape
The Agape you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
Dive with all your might!
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear you
君がくれる Agape
The Agape you give me
力のかぎり
With all my strength...
Dive!
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
The radio wave tempo has increased, and we are totally electrified!
あなたにもわすれたいこと かなしいこと あるのかしらね
I wonder if you also have things you want to forget or things that make you sad.
識らない映画なのに涙をながすのは ドラマチックが足りていないからよ
Shedding tears for a movie you don't even know is because you lack drama.
そんな愚にも付かないこと くだらないこと 考えてばかりね
I do nothing but think of such silly, trivial things.
雨が上がれば愛もその横顔も
When the rain clears, your love and your profile...
誰かのものになるのでしょう
...will probably belong to someone else.
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部今夜のためよ
Even this fake foundation is all for tonight.
なのに一体全体如何して如何して何故何故怒ってんの
Yet why on earth are you so angry?
不安定なカンテラ何処まで行くの
Where are you going with that unstable lantern?
あなた一切合切放り去ってもう
You've cast everything completely aside already.
冗談じゃあないわ
This is no joke!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって如何にもならんぜ
Even when the time comes, nothing can be done.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコり化するだけ
Vague truths will only turn into melancholy.
あたしをさあ掻っ攫って今テイクオンミー
So come sweep me away, take on me now.
はあ ちゃんちゃらおかしい法度ばっかでしょ
Hah, they're all just ridiculous rules, aren't they?
食指がびくともしないわ
I don't feel tempted at all.
実態の無い感情放っておいたって
Even if I leave these formless feelings alone...
策略なんてありゃあせんのに何故
...there's no scheme behind them, so why?
あああもう懲り懲りよ
Ah, I've had quite enough!
あたしの喝となる気質も
Even my inspiring temperament...
じっと堪えて取り繕ってはとうとう臨界点
...holding it in and patching it up, it's finally at its limit.
年がら年中リップサービス 鈍感カマしては辟易
Lip service all year round, acting dense makes me sick of it.
どんがらがっしゃんフィールガールは涙の目にも鬼
The crash-and-burn feel girl is relentless even with tears in her eyes.
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいで あなたの話は一向に聴き取れない
Now, because of the music in my head, I can't hear a word you say.
少しは真当なこと言って
Say something that actually makes sense.
回り出すターンテーブル ねぇ全部忘れさせてよ
The turntable starts spinning, hey, make me forget everything.
だけど一体全体如何して如何して何故何故怒ってんの
But why on earth are you so angry?
不安定なカンテラ消えないままで
The unstable lantern remains lit.
あなた一口両舌食い違ってもう保存
You're double-tongued and we're totally crossed.
冗談じゃあないわ保存
This is no joke!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ保存
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!保存
その時が来たって如何にもならんぜ保存
Even when the time comes, nothing can be done.保存
曖昧な本当なんてメランコり化するだけ保存
Vague truths will only turn into melancholy.保存
あたしを今保存
Me, right now...保存
冗談じゃあないわ保存
This is no joke!保存
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ保存,s:
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!保存
その時が来たって如何にもならんぜ保存
Even when the time comes, nothing can be done.保存
不甲斐ないわ保存
How disappointing.保存
感情なんてランドリーで落とすだけ保存
Feelings can just be washed away in the laundry.保存
あたしと確かめ合ってイエロー・マジック保存
Confirm it with me, yellow magic.保存
あい やいやい保存
Ah, iya-iya...保存
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ保存
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!保存
その時が来たって如何にもならんぜ保存
Even when the time comes, nothing can be done.保存
曖昧な本当なんてメランコり化するだけ保存
Vague truths will only turn into melancholy.保存
あたしをさあ掻っ攫って今テイクオンミー保存
So come sweep me away, take on me now.保存
AZKi 8th Birthday Live CROSSOVER!
最後はチームみんなで歌い上げます
Lastly, everyone in each team will sing together!
平成 赤チーム
Heisei Red Team!
アニメ「とある科学の超電磁砲」より、未だ愛され続けるアニソンの王道
From the anime "A Certain Scientific Railgun", the classic anime song that continues to be loved...
only my railgun
続いて令和 青チーム
Next, Reiwa Blue Team!
アニメ「呪術廻戦」より、鮮烈でエモーショナルな青春ソング
From the anime "Jujutsu Kaisen", a vivid and emotional youth song...
青のすみか
Where Our Blue Is!
ステージでぶつかる電撃と呪力
Lightning and cursed energy clashing on stage.
２曲続けてどうぞ！
Please enjoy the two songs back-to-back!
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Fire away! The dreams engraved in your heart...
未来さえ置き去りにして
...leaving even the future behind!
限界など知らない 意味無い！
I know no limits, they're meaningless!
この能力が光散らす
My power will scatter light...
その先に遥かな想いを
...sending my distant feelings ahead!
歩いてきた この道を
If I can only look back...
振り返ることしか
...on this path I walked...
出来ないなら... 今ここで
...then right here, right now...
全てを壊せる
I can destroy it all!
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
As the streets descend into darkness...
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
...how far will people go to resist?
加速するその痛みから
From this intensifying pain...
誰かをきっと守れるよ
...I'm sure I can protect someone.
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Looking! I'll blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
Only my railgun can shoot it, right now!
身体中を 光の速さで
Running through my body at the speed of light...
光の速さで
...at the speed of light,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
a certain premonition ran through.
掴め! 望むものなら残さず 輝ける自分らしさで
Seize it! If it's your wish, leave nothing behind with your shining self!
信じてるよ あの日の誓いを
I believe in the vow made that day,
この瞳に光る涙 それさえも強さになるから
for even the tears glittering in these eyes will become my strength!
立ち止まると 少しだけ 感じる切なさに
When I stop, for just a moment, in the sadness I feel...
戸惑う事 無いなんて 嘘はつかないよ
I won't lie and say I never hesitate.
宇宙に舞うコインが描く 放物線が決める運命
The parabola drawn by a coin dancing in the sky decides our fate.
打ち出した答えが今日も 私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer shot forth still runs through my heart today.
Sparkling! The shiny lights awake true desire.
Sparkling! The shiny lights awaken true desire.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 必ず
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it, without fail,
貫いてく 途惑うことなく
piercing through without hesitation.
傷ついても 走り続ける
Even if I get hurt, I'll keep running.
狙え! 凛と煌めく視線は 狂い無く闇を切り裂く
Aim! That dignified, glittering gaze tears through the darkness unerringly.
迷いなんて 吹き飛ばせばいい
Just blow away any doubts!
この心が叫ぶ限り 誰ひとり邪魔などさせない
As long as my heart screams, I won't let anyone get in my way!
儚く舞う 無数の願いは
The countless wishes that dance transiently
この両手に 積もってゆく
will gather in these hands.
切り裂く闇に 見えてくるのは
What I see in the tearing darkness
重く深く 切ない記憶
is a heavy, deep, painful memory.
色褪せてく 現実に揺れる
Swaying in a fading reality,
絶望には 負けたくない
I don't want to lose to despair.
私が今 私であること
That I am myself right now,
胸を張って 全て誇れる!
I'll hold my head high and be proud of it all!
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search a way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it, right now!
身体中を 光の速さで
Running through my entire body at the speed of light,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
is a certain premonition.
放て! 心に刻んだ夢を 未来さえ置き去りにして
Release it! Leaving behind even the future and the dreams engraved in your heart!
限界など知らない 意味無い!
I know no limits, they're meaningless!
この能力が光散らす その先に遥かな想いを
This power will scatter light toward those distant feelings!
青のすみか
作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ
Where Our Blue Is
Lyrics & Composition: Tatsuya Kitani
どこまでも続くような青の季節は
The blue season that seems to stretch on forever...
四つ並ぶ眼の前を遮るものは何もない
...has nothing blocking the four eyes lined up in front.
アスファルト、蝉時雨を反射して
Reflecting off the asphalt, the shower of cicada cries...
きみという沈黙が聞こえなくなる
...makes the silence called 'you' no longer audible.
この日々が色褪せる
Even as these days fade away,
僕と違うきみの匂いを知ってしまっても
and I come to know your scent, different from mine...
置き忘れてきた永遠の底に
...at the bottom of the eternity we left behind,
今でも青が棲んでいる
the blue still resides.
今でも青は澄んでいる
The blue is still clear.
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayers or the words,
近づけるのに、届かなかった
though they got close, they never reached.
まるで、静かな恋のような
Just like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
in a color like summer running down our cheeks,
きみを呪う言葉がずっと 喉の奥につかえてる
the words that bind you are forever stuck in my throat...
「また会えるよね」って 声にならない声
...a silent voice saying, "We'll meet again, right?"
昼下がり、じめつく風の季節は
In the mid-afternoon, during the muggy wind season,
想い馳せる、まだ何者でもなかった僕らの肖像
I think back to the portraits of us, when we were still nobody.
何もかも分かち合えたはずだった
We should have been able to share everything,
あの日から少しずつ
but little by little since that day,
きみと違う僕という呪いが肥えていく
the curse of me being different from you has grown.
きみの笑顔の奥の憂いを
The sorrow hidden behind your smile...
見落としたこと、悔やみ尽くして
...I completely regret having overlooked it.
徒花と咲いて散っていくきみに
To you, who bloom as a transient flower and wither...
さよなら
Goodbye.
今でも青が棲んでいる
Even now, the blue still resides.
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, the blue remains clear.
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayers or words,
近づけるのに、届かなかった
they couldn't get us any closer, they couldn't reach.
まるで、静かな恋のような
It was like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
in the midst of colors like the summer that ran down our cheeks.
きみを呪う言葉が
The words cursing you
ずっと喉の奥につかえてる
remain stuck in the back of my throat.
「また会えるよね」って
"We'll meet again," you said,
声にならない声
with a voice that couldn't be heard.
無限に膨張する銀河の星の粒のように
Like the grains of stars in an infinitely expanding galaxy,
指の隙間を零れた
it slipped through the gaps between my fingers.
はい！ということでここまですね、一気にノンストップでお送りしました！
Alright! And with that, we've brought you a non-stop medley up to this point!
いや、平成も、令和も、いや名曲ばかりでしたね！
Man, whether from the Heisei or Reiwa era, they were all truly masterpieces!
どうでしたか？好きな曲はありましたか？
How was it? Did you hear any of your favorite songs?
そして、みんな、どっちのチームが良かったかな？
And also, everyone, which team did you think was better?
ほうほうほうほう...
I see, I see...
えっとですね、この、このね、今、後ろのこのハートのステージね。
So, as you can see, this heart stage behind me...
はい、こちらのハートに映し出された色で
Yes, based on the color displayed on this heart,
どっちのチームが勝ったのか、決まります！
the winning team will be decided!
ぜひ、みんなコメントで、どっちが良かったか、教えてください！
Everyone, please let me know in the comments which team you liked better!
ええ？決められない？
What? You can't decide?
いやいや、そこはね、ちょっとね、決めて...
No, no, you've got to choose one...
あ、すごい、この2色にね、分かれておりますけれども、しっかり決めていただかないと、はい。
Oh, wow, the comments are split into two colors, but you really have to make a choice.
今日はね、あの平成VS令和となっております！
Because today, it's Heisei versus Reiwa!
はい、ということで、勝ったのは、平成赤チームか？
Alright, with that said, is the winner the Heisei Red Team?
それとも、令和青チームか？
Or is it the Reiwa Blue Team?
一体、どっちかな？
Which one could it be?
それじゃあ、行くよ！さあ、結果はこちら！
Here we go! Let's see the results!
どっちかな？
Which one is it?
お？え？
Oh? Huh?
なんか、紫になっちゃったんですけど！
Wait, it turned purple!
紫って、紫ってどっちですか？
What does purple even mean? Which side is purple?
うーん、もうこれは、あの、赤チームも良かったし、青チームも良かったということで、
Well, I guess this means both the Red Team and the Blue Team were so good...
すべてフュージョンして、紫になってしまった！
...that they fused together and turned purple!
ということで、いや、みんなあの、たくさん歌ったし、
So, since everyone sang their hearts out...
ま、みんな最高だったってことにね、します！
...we'll just say that everyone was absolutely amazing!
いや、なんか、なんか、みんなのおかげで、
Wow, somehow, thanks to all of you...
なんか、パワーが、パワーが溜まってきた気がするなー！
I feel like... I feel like power is welling up inside me!
お、気がするー！
I really feel it!
ふふふっ、ということで、新衣装です！
Hehehe, and with that, here is my new outfit!
えー、みんなのコメ...
So, let's see everyone's comm...
なんと、全部あずきの魔力になっちゃった！
Wow, everything has turned into AZKi's magic!
見てください、どうですか？
Take a look! What do you think?
しっぽ、しっぽも生えてるんです保存
A tail... I even have a tail now!
フリフリフリフリ
Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle!
どうですか？
How does it look?
はい、ということで今回は
Yes! So, for this live show,
えー、小悪魔衣装を仕立てていただきました！
I had this little devil outfit made for me!
どうでしょうか？
What do you think?
どうでしょうか？魔力…
What do you think? Magic power?
魔王？ふふふ、小悪魔です
Demon King? Haha, I'm a little devil!
はい
Yes!
今回ですね、新衣装はこちらの小悪魔衣装！
My new outfit this time is this little devil outfit!
可愛いでしょ？
Cute, right?
たくさんスクリーンショットも撮ってくださいね！
Please take lots of screenshots!
ということで、この衣装でね
So, with this outfit,
せっかくなので、あの曲を歌っていきたいなと思います！
since we're here, I want to sing that song!
もしかしたらね、小悪魔ですから
And you know, since I'm a little devil,
この姿なら、魔法とかも使えちゃうんじゃないのかな？
in this form, maybe I can even use magic?
ということで
With that said...
ではですね
Now, then...
次の曲、聴いてください！
Please listen to the next song!
召喚！
Summon!
自分の過去に囚われ迷って
Trapped and lost in my own past,
そうじゃないよと言い聞かせて全てを
I tell myself it's not like that and...
自由に操れるかなんて
I wonder if I can control everything freely.
分からないよと空は霞んで正解はどこ？
"I don't know," I say, as the sky hazes over. Where is the right answer?
僕の手のひらに残る大事なもの
The precious things remaining in my palm...
忘れない記憶 何度でも
...are unforgettable memories, over and over again.
君を守り抜くと叫んで
I scream that I'll protect you to the very end!
巻き戻しの中 掴んだ愛はそう
Yes, the love I grabbed amidst rewinding time...
離しはしないから
...is something I will never let go.
散りばめた想い 今一度きりの願いへ
My scattered feelings now head towards a one-time wish.
次への僕に託したよ保存
I've entrusted it to my future self.
いつかの約束 光の道しるべになる
The promise we made will become a beacon of light.
誓いをさあ君のため
Now, I offer this vow for your sake...
最期まで
...until the very end!
涙さえ力に変えてきっと描いていた望む未来へ
Changing even my tears into strength, surely towards the desired future I drew...
繋ぐよ
...I will connect us!
想像を超える事態に狂って
Going mad in a situation beyond my imagination,
爪を立ててはもがき足掻いて心は
clawing, struggling, and fighting back, my heart...
人生の過ちをもう何回
...wondering how many times I will repeat...
繰り返しては嫌いになって泣いてても
...the mistakes of my life, growing to hate it and crying.
君の憧れはいつも輝いてた
Yet your aspiration was always shining bright.
I'll come back (yeah)
To your future (go away)
僕は抗うだろう運命に
I will fight against destiny.
Breaking out (yeah)
Breaking down (yeah go away)
諦めちゃいないから
Because I haven't given up!
結ばれた意思は 独りきりじゃない強さへ
Our bound wills head toward a strength that is no longer alone.
紡いだ糸を手繰り寄せ
I draw in the spun threads.
見つけた瞳は 理想を現実に変える
The eyes I found will turn ideals into reality.
世界はそう君のため
Yes, the world is for your sake...
最初から
...from the very beginning!
胸に抱いた思い出とずっと あの日から続く決意で
With the memories held in my heart, and the determination continuing from that day...
飛べるよ Redo
...I can fly! Redo!
あずきち生誕祭、まだまだいけますか？！
AZKi-chi's Birthday Celebration! Can you still keep going?!
盛り上がっていこう！
Let's get fired up!
君がたとえ僕のこと
Even if you...
忘れても
...forget about me,
僕はもう忘れない 誰も傷つけない
I will never forget again, and I won't let anyone get hurt!
消えそうな過去を救い出すための時間よ
Oh time, meant for rescuing a past that's about to fade away...
ここから始まれ
...begin from right here!
巡りゆく一瞬を 今一度きりの願いへ
This cycling moment, now towards a one-time wish.
確かに僕は託された
Surely, it has been entrusted to me.
いつかの約束 光の道しるべになる
The promise we made will become a beacon of light.
誓いをさあ
So, let's make a vow...
君のため
...for your sake...
最期まで
...until the very end.
涙さえ力に変えてきっと
I'll surely turn even my tears into strength...
描いていた望む未来へ
...and connect them to the future I envisioned...
繋ぐよ
...the future I desire.
わー！
Yeah!
ということで、聴いていただいてありがとうございました！
And with that, thank you so much for listening!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
今日は小悪魔衣装になって、魔法で召喚しちゃいました！
Today, I put on this little devil outfit and summoned you with magic!
召喚されちゃいました！こあずきー！
I've been summoned! Ko-AZKi!
わー！ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
ということでね、皆さんもご存知だと思いますが、アニソン界のエース
As I'm sure you all know, the ace of the anime song world...
鈴木このみさんに異世界転生してもらいました！
...Konomi Suzuki-san, has reincarnated into this parallel world for us!
召喚されましたー！
I've been summoned!
誕生日をね、今日はお祝いしたいなと、思って、参りました！
Today is your birthday, and I came here wanting to celebrate it with you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ということでですね、一緒に歌った曲は
So, the song we just sang together...
『Re:ゼロから始める異世界生活』の1stシーズンOPテーマ、『Redo』でした！
...was "Redo," the 1st season OP theme of "Re:ZERO -Starting Life in Another World-"!
イェーイ！いかがでしたでしょうか？
Yay! How did you all like it?
ドキドキしたなぁ！
That was so nerve-wracking!
いや、私もめっちゃドキドキした！
Honestly, I was super nervous too!
『Redo』を人と歌ったことがあんまりなくって...
I've rarely sung "Redo" with someone else before...
えっ！
Oh, really?
すごい怖い顔をして歌ってないか、すごい心配です。
I was really worried that I was making a scary face while singing.
貴重な、貴重な経験ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for such a rare, precious experience!
あずきちと歌えて楽しかった！
It was so much fun singing with Azukichi!
あずきちって呼んでくれてるんですよ、みんな！
Everyone, she's calling me "Azukichi"!
そうなんです。
That's right.
あずきはね、このみんって呼んでるんですけど。
And I call her "Konomin."
いや、実はね、出会いのきっかけはですね...
Actually, the catalyst for us meeting was...
いや、もうずっとあずきは元々大好きなんですけど、このみんがね、あの...
Well, I've always loved her, but Konomin actually...
『異世界かるてっと』の...
...in "Isekai Quartet"...
そう！そう！『異世界かるてっと3』のエンディングテーマ...
Yes! Yes! The ending theme of "Isekai Quartet 3"...
『君色僕色』のカルテットバージョンを作ることになりまして。
...we were going to make a quartet version of "Kimiiro Bokuiro."
そう！
Right!
で、その時にあの、会社の人から
And at that time, someone from the company told me...
「誰か一人好きな人を召喚できる権利を差し上げます」って言われて...
"We'll give you the right to summon one person of your choice."
「はっ、そんな機会あるなら、あずきちにお願いしてみたい」って。
I thought, "If I have that chance, I'd love to ask Azukichi!"
ええー！嬉しい！
Aww, I'm so happy!
私、ライブも元々見てたんで、いつかコラボしたいなって気持ちがずっとあったので。
I'd watched her live shows before, so I always wanted to collaborate someday.
そこでラブコールをして、叶いまして。
So I sent her a love call, and it came true.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
まさかね、そんなことがありまして、そこからコラボ配信とか...
I never imagined that would happen! From there, we did collab streams...
あの、あずきもね、このみんのライブ見に行かせてもらったりとか。
...and I also got to go see Konomin's live concerts.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あとはね、ラーメンの...
And then, there was the ramen...
ラーメンの汁をね、飛ばしました。
...ramen broth splash incident!
あの、配信の日にそういう話をしていて、すぐLINEを交換して...
We talked about that on the stream day, immediately exchanged LINE IDs...
すぐラーメンの汁を飛ばして...
...and then immediately splashed ramen broth on each other!
汁を飛ばして、すぐそのあと...
We splashed broth, and right after that...
焼肉も行って...
...we also went to yakiniku...
油を飛ばして！
...and splashed oil!
油を飛ばして、アフタヌーンティーにも行きました。
We splashed oil, and also went to afternoon tea.
一応オシャレなこともしたい、結構ね...
We wanted to do something fancy too. We've actually...
そうなんです、なんと仲良くさせていただいております。
That's right, we've become really close friends.
濃厚なお付き合いで。
A deep friendship!
そう、濃厚なお付き合いをさせてもらっておりまして。
Yes, we've been enjoying a very deep friendship.
なんと今日、ついにバーチャル空間に来てくれました！
And today, she finally came to this virtual space!
初めてです！ありがとう！なんて楽しい空間なんだ！
It's my first time! Thank you! What a fun space this is!
嬉しい！嬉しすぎる！
I'm so happy! Too happy!
なんか、この空間は魔法が使えそうって聞いたんですけど、本当ですか？
I heard that you can use magic in this space. Is that true?
使っちゃいますか？このみんは一体どんな魔法を...
Shall we use some? What kind of magic does Konomin have...
あの、私、僭越ながら、一つだけ魔法を覚えてきたんですよ。
I've actually taken the liberty of learning just one magic spell.
えっ！なんとこの日のために！
Oh! Just for today!
これだけ使える。あの、これはでも、みんなと一緒じゃないと完成しない魔法なんで。
This is the only one I can use. But it's a spell that can't be completed without everyone.
ぜひあずきちへのラブを込めて、一緒に歌って魔法を完成させてください。
So please, channel your love for Azukichi, sing along, and help complete the magic!
せーの！
Ready, go!
Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday dear あずきち
Happy Birthday dear Azukichi
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
Happy Birthday to you
あずきち、仕上げをお願いします！
Azukichi, please do the honors of finishing it!
仕上げ！はい！
The finish! Okay!
ふーっ！
Fuu~!
このみんは、炎の使い手でした！
Konomin was a wielder of fire!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！まさか歌までプレゼントしていただけるなんて。
Thank you so much! I never expected to receive a song as a gift.
もう、ここで命尽きても...
I could die happy right here...
ダメです！ダメです！命尽きちゃダメなんです！
No, you can't! You can't die!
実は、皆さん今日、重大告知と...
Actually, everyone, today I have a major announcement...
書いてあると思うんですけどね、サムネに。
I think it's already written on the thumbnail, though.
2人から重大告知が
We have a major announcement...
ございます！
...for you!
やったー！
Yay!
なんと！2人のオリジナルコラボ楽曲が出ます！
Believe it or not, we are releasing an original collaboration song!
やったー！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
いいんですか？いいんですか？
Is this really okay? Are you sure?
ということで、タイトルは、せーの、最強未来衝動！
And so, the title is... One, two, "Saikyou Mirai Shoudou"!
という、なんだか強そうなタイトルですね。
That sounds like a really powerful title.
強い曲ですね。強い曲です。
It's a strong song. Yes, it's a strong song.
ということで、なんと、今日初披露させていただきます！
And so, we will be performing it for the first time today!
頑張ろう！
Let's do our best!
それでは早速、聴いてもらえますか？
Now then, without further ado, will you listen to it?
はい！
Yes!
それでは、聴いてください！
Now then, please listen to it!
だから just fly to the star
So just fly to the star
もっと wow wow
More, wow wow
世界中で proudy glow
Proudly glowing all over the world
存在など歌い切って無い無い
Singing out our existence completely, with no doubts
壊れても関係ない
Even if we break, it doesn't matter
そっと触れるよ 生まれたての星へ
Gently touching the newborn star
囁きながら 願い重ねた宇宙(そら)
Whispering as our wishes pile up in the sky
ほどけた軌道は 誰も知らない場所へ
The unraveled orbit leads to a place no one knows
微かな記憶と夢を この声に込めて
Putting faint memories and dreams into this voice
今を 過去を
The present, the past...
未来を辿る
...tracing the future.
一瞬を 一生を
An instant, a lifetime...
この手で掴む 超 BIG！BANG！
...we'll seize it with our hands, Super Big Bang!
ただこのまま果てまで溶けちゃって
Just melting away to the very end like this
切り裂かれたような衝動
An impulse like being torn apart
抱かれて染まって振り切って
Embraced, dyed, shaking it all off
まだ まだ ほら また星を締め付ける
Still, still, look, tightening around the stars again
君と絡まってみようか
Shall we get intertwined with you?
止まらないよ 最強未来衝動
It won't stop, the strongest future impulse
ただ ただけ、ただ ただけ 剥がれ落ちてく
Just, just, just, just peeling and falling away
広がって 咲いて 駆け出して飛んで
Spreading, blooming, running out, and flying
君と just fly to the star
With you, just fly to the star
もっと wow wow
More, wow wow
無重力で dreamy show
A dreamy show in zero gravity
運命など待ち切れ無い無い
We can't wait for things like fate
壊れても関係ない
Even if we break, it doesn't matter
そっと祈るよ 幾千年の星へ
Gently praying to the stars of thousands of years
彷徨いながら 僕ら出会えたんだ
While wandering around, we were able to meet
燃え尽きる前に 誰も彼も急ぐよ
Before burning out, everyone is rushing
確かな希望と信念を この声に込めて
Putting definite hope and conviction into this voice
星よ 光れ
Stars, shine
闇を照らせ
Illuminate the darkness
歌よ 響け
Song, resound
遥か彼方へ
To the far distance...
超 BIG！BANG！
...Super Big Bang!
引力にさあ 導かれ
Come, guided by gravity
この手を繋いだら
If we hold hands
それだけでいい
That's all we need
聞いて！鳴り止まない絶唱
Listen! The endless vocal masterpiece
愛して 焦がして 振り切って
Loving, burning, shaking it all off
まだ まだ ほら また宇宙(そら)を駆け巡る
Still, still, look, running around the universe again
君を狂わせてみようか
Shall I drive you crazy?
止まらないで 絶対未来衝動
Don't stop, absolute future impulse
ただ ただ ただ ただ 生まれ落ちてく
Just, just, just, just being born and falling
そばにいて
Stay by my side
触れて
Touch me
輝いて
Shining
消えて
Disappearing
生きることは
To live is...
銀河を旅する story
...a story of traveling the galaxy
どこまでも走っていく
I'll run to the ends of the earth
どこまでも燃やしていく
I'll keep burning forever
どこまでも生命(いのち)がある限り
Wherever we go, as long as there is life
叫べ
Scream!
伝えたい この淡い衝動
I want to convey this faint impulse
伝えたい この熱い衝動を
I want to convey this burning impulse
衝動を
...this impulse.
ゆけ
Go,
go!
ここ
From
から
here,
次元を超えていく
we'll cross dimensions,
超えていく
surpassing them,
surpassing them.
歌え！
Sing!
この衝動はきっと
This impulse will surely
抱かれて染まって振り切って
be embraced, stained, and shaken off.
まだ
Still,
ほら<,s:
look,
また
again,
星を締め付ける
tightening the stars.
君と絡まってみようか
Shall we try getting tangled together?
止まらないよ最強未来衝動
The strongest future impulse won't stop.
ただ ただ ただ ただ
Just, just, just, just
剥がれ落ちてく
peeling away.
広がって
Spreading,
咲いて
blooming,
駆け出して
running out,
飛んで
and flying!
だから just fly to the star
So just fly to the star,
もっと wow wow
more wow wow.
世界中で proudy glow
Proudly glow all over the world,
存在など歌い切って無い無い
there's no existence left to sing of.
壊れても関係ない
I don't care if I break.
はーい！ということで、新曲を披露させていただきました！
Yes! And with that, we have performed our new song!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
カッコいい曲になりましたね、このみん！
It turned out to be such a cool song, Konomin!
ええ曲！
A great song!
A great song indeed!
ということでですね、『最強未来衝動』
So, "Saikyou Mirai Shoudou"...
本日この後7月2日0時からデジタルリリースされます！
will be released digitally today at midnight on July 2nd!
わー！
Yay!
ちょっとせっかくなんで
Since we have this opportunity...
この曲、実は
this song is actually...
2人ね
the two of us...
2人で作詞を
we wrote the lyrics together!
そうなんですよ
That's right.
いたしました！
Yes, we did!
2日間、一緒に缶詰状態になって...
We were cooped up together for two days...
一緒に缶詰になって部屋にね、閉じこもって
Yes, locked up together in a room...
このみんと一緒に、あの、作詞をするという
working on writing the lyrics together with Konomin.
貴重な、大変貴重な経験をさせていただきました
It was a very valuable, truly precious experience.
いや私も、なんかすごいい、あの、楽しかったし
For me too, it was incredibly fun, and...
こう、仲も深まったんじゃないかっていう
I feel like our bond grew much deeper.
そう、仲も深まったんじゃないかっていう！
Yes, our bond definitely grew deeper!
気がしております
That's how I feel.
嬉しいです！はい、そんな楽曲ですので、ぜひぜひ
I'm so happy! Since it's that kind of song, please...
隅々まで聴いてほしいなと思います！
listen to every single detail of it!
お願いします！
Please check it out!
というわけで、今日はね、この世界に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Anyway, thank you so much for coming to this world today!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
どうでしたか？どうでしたか？
How was it? How did it feel?
正直に言っていい？
Can I be honest?
うん
Yeah.
めっちゃ楽しい！
It was super fun!
いや、もうなんか順応してる！
Wow, you've already adapted so well!
そう、そうなの。なんかね、あの、なんでも炎とか出せちゃうんだって
Yeah, exactly. I heard you can even shoot fire out of nowhere.
そう、出せちゃうし
Yes, you can!
最高！
That's awesome!
え、ちょっとさ、最後にさ、2人でこのハートマークを作りませんか？
Hey, before we end, why don't we make a heart sign together?
やりたい！
I'd love to!
じゃあ行くよ！
All right, here we go!
せーの、はい！
Ready, set, go!
いいんじゃないでしょうか！
I think we did great!
いいね！
Nice!
みんな撮れた？スクショもね、お願いしますね！
Did everyone get that? Please take screenshots!
はい！ということでこのみんと一緒にハートを作ったということで
All right! Now that we've made a heart with Konomin...
最後に、このみんから告知などありますか？ぜひ！
finally, Konomin, do you have any announcements? Go ahead!
はい！えっと、まず7月11日に、アニサマ！
Yes! First, on July 11th, Animelo Summer Live!
夏の、アニメの祭典が行われます！
The big summer anime music festival will be held!
そちらに出ます！
I will be performing there!
お、すごい、すごい、すごい！
Oh, wow, that's amazing!
はい、フェスモードな感じで、アニソンですよね<,s:
Yes, it's total festival mode with anime songs!
そう、アニソン！
Yes, anime songs!
そう、アチチナ、アチチナあの、歌で炎をバンバン出せたらいいなと思いますので
Yes, I hope to fire up the stage and make it super hot with my performance!
ここでもね、現実でも炎を出してってくれます
She'll fire things up in the real world too!
お願いします！
Please support me!
あとは、私、あの、ライブが決まってまして
Also, I have another live concert coming up.
11月7日土曜日に東京SGCホールにて
On Saturday, November 7th, at Tokyo SGC Hall...
アニソンコレクションプラス、アニソンだけを歌うライブをやります！
I'll hold Anisong Collection Plus, where I only sing anime songs!
なんですって！
What? Really?!
そうだから、今日あの、あずきちゃんが、あずきちが、あの...
That's why today, AZKi-chan was...
今日アニソン、ずっと歌ってて
singing anime songs the whole time.
そう、今日はアニソンをテーマにしたライブとなっております
Yes, today's live concert is themed around anime songs.
めっちゃ楽しいじゃんって思いながら、私もそんな一日を過ごそうかなと思ってます
I was thinking, "That's so fun!" and want to spend a day like that too.
応援してます！
I'm rooting for you!
あの代表曲ばっかり流れるそんな...
It will be filled with all my signature songs...
そんな、行かなきゃ！
Wow, I absolutely have to go!
ぜひ来てほしい！
Please come by!
行かなきゃ！
I definitely will!
ぜひぜひ！ということで、ぜひあの、詳しくはアカウントをチェックしていただいて
Please do! Yes, for details, please check my official account...
一緒にアニソンまみれの1日過ごしましょう。よろしくお願いします！
and let's spend a day covered in anime songs. Thank you!
行きたい、行きたい！
I want to go, I really do!
はい！ということで
Yes! And with that...
非常に残念なんですが、そろそろこのみんを元の世界に戻さないと、アニサマも...
it's really sad, but I have to send Konomin back, or Animelo...
名残惜しい
I don't want to leave...
アニソンコレクションもできないので
and Anisong Collection won't be able to happen.
またご飯行こう！
Let's grab food again!
ご飯行こうで！
Let's definitely do that!
行こう行こう
Yes, let's go!
やった！じゃあちょっとね、あの魔法を使ってこのみを元の世界に戻したいと思います。今日はありがとうございました！
Yay! Now, I'll use some magic to send Konomin back to her world. Thank you for today!
ありがとうございました！おめでとう！
Thank you so much! And congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あー、消えちゃった！
Ah, she disappeared!
はい！ということでですね、えー、サプライズスペシャルゲスト鈴木このみさんに来ていただきました！
All right! That was our surprise special guest, Suzuki Konomin!
えー、今日のライブいかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you all enjoy today's live concert?
本当にね、内容盛りだくさんで...
The content is really packed, and...
そうだ、この新しい
Oh right, about this new...
小悪魔衣装のこと、あんまり話せなかったので
little devil outfit, I couldn't talk much about it,
この後メン限でゆっくり見てもらえたらと思います
so I hope you can take a look at it slowly in the members-only stream after this.
実は色んなアクセサリーや、差分があります！ということで
Actually, there are various accessories and variations! So...
ぜひメン限もよろしくお願いします！
please join the members-only stream as well!
そして、皆様
And, everyone,
最後に
lastly...
AZKiから、みんなに
From AZKi, to everyone,
嬉しいお知らせです！
here is a happy announcement!
こちら！どうぞ！
Here it is! Go ahead!
傷ついた感情も 連れて行くから
I'll take even my hurt feelings along with me...
そっと響くファンファーレが 新しい未来を感じてる
as the softly echoing fanfare makes me feel a new future.
怖がったって 進むしかないでしょう 遠くまで
Even if I'm scared, I have no choice but to move forward, far away.
届け この祈りよ 光となれ
Reach out, this prayer, become the light.
もっと もっと 少しずつでもいい 優しいという答えを
More and more, even little by little is fine, the answer called kindness...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
more, more, more, more!
お待たせしました！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
AZKiソロライブ2025「Departure」
AZKi Solo Live 2025 "Departure"
Blu-ray発売決定！
Blu-ray release decided!
開拓者のみんなと紡いだあのステージが、何度でも見返せます！
You can rewatch that stage we spun together with all Pioneers as many times as you want!
本日から受注受付が開始です！
Pre-orders start today!
続いて、告知二つ目！
Next up, the second announcement!
AZKiの歴史を彩るアルバム二作品の再販が、
The re-release of the two albums coloring AZKi's history
本日7月1日より全国流通スタート！
starts nationwide distribution today, July 1st!
対象タイトルは「Without U」と「Re:Creating world」です！
The target titles are "Without U" and "Re:Creating world"!
最後！告知三つ目！
Lastly! The third announcement!
AZKi誕生日記念2026 グッズ情報！
AZKi Birthday Commemorative 2026 Merchandise info!
今回はお披露目された小悪魔衣装にちなんだグッズが盛りだくさんです！
This time, there is plenty of merch related to the newly revealed little devil outfit!
イラストは信澤収先生に描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
The illustrations were drawn by Nobusawa Osamu-sensei! Thank you very much!
それでは、詳細を見ていきましょう！
Now, let's take a look at the details!
まずは、こちら！「2層アクリルパネル」！
First of all, this! "2-layer Acrylic Panel"!
小悪魔衣装のキービジュアルをアクリルパネルにしました！
We made the little devil outfit key visual into an acrylic panel!
2層になっているので、立体的に見えます！
Since it has two layers, it looks three-dimensional!
ステンドグラスの神秘的な美しさと、小悪魔衣装が見せるギャップを楽しんでください！
Please enjoy the gap between the mysterious beauty of the stained glass and the little devil outfit!
続いては、こちら！「ランダムラバーキーホルダー」！
Next up, this! "Random Rubber Keychain"!
この後のメン限でも詳しく見せちゃうんですけど、
I'll show them in detail in the members-only stream later, but...
今回の新衣装、実はバリエーションがいっぱいあるので、
this new outfit actually has a lot of variations,
ラバーキーホルダーにしてもらいました！
so we had them made into rubber keychains!
君のお気に入りはどのAZKiかな？
Which AZKi is your favorite?
イラストはねとら先生に描いていただきました！
The illustrations were drawn by Netora-sensei!
続いては、こちら！「ぬいぐるみキーホルダー」！
Next up, this! "Plush Keychain"!
こちらも小悪魔衣装バージョンとなっております！
This one is also in the little devil outfit version!
使い魔みたいな茶目っ気のある表情になっているので、
It has a playful expression like a familiar, so...
ぜひ相棒として連れ歩いてください！
please take it along with you as your partner!
続いては、こちら！「おそろいブレスレット」！
Next up, this! "Matching Bracelet"!
小悪魔衣装をモチーフにしたデザインのブレスレットです！
This bracelet's design is themed after the little devil outfit!
日常の中でさりげなく推しを身にまとうのはもちろん、
Of course, it's great for casually wearing your favorite in daily life,
普段アクセサリーを付けない方には、
and for those who don't usually wear accessories,
新衣装の再現コレクションとしてもおすすめです！
it's also recommended as a reproduction collection of the new outfit!
続いては、こちら！「ASMRボイス」！
Next up, this! "ASMR Voice"!
ボイスタイトルは、「小悪魔チャーミング」！
The voice title is "Little Devil Charming"!
AZKiが小悪魔っぽく魔法をかけちゃう、
AZKi will cast a spell on you like a little devil...
そんなもしものお話のASMRボイスです！
It's an ASMR voice of such a "what if" story!
そして、フルセット購入特典もございます！
And there are also benefits for purchasing the full set!
信澤収先生イラストの、AZKiのタロット風カードと、
A tarot-style card of AZKi illustrated by Nobusawa Osamu-sensei,
特典ASMRボイスです！
and a bonus ASMR voice!
数量限定バージョンは、直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りです！
The limited quantity version includes a handwritten autograph & foil-stamped duplicated message!
通常バージョンは、箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りです！
The regular version includes a foil-stamped duplicated autograph & message!
ということで、以上、嬉しいお知らせでした！
So, that was all the happy announcements!
この後はメン限でアンコールライブ！
After this, we have the encore live stream for members!
まだメン限に入っていない方も、まだ間に合うので、ぜひ入ってみてください！
Even if you haven't joined yet, you can still make it, so please join us!
実は今回の新衣装、
Actually, for this new outfit...
みんなにまだ見せていない、あんな姿や、こんな姿
I have some looks that I haven't shown everyone yet,
があるので、見に来てくれたら嬉しいです！
so I'd be happy if you came to watch!
誕生日たくさんお祝いしてくれてありがとう！ライブも見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday! Thank you for watching the live stream!
それじゃあ、この後メン限で会おうね！バイバイ！
Well then, see you in the members-only stream after this! Bye-bye!
AZKi 8th Birthday Live Crossover - 平成 vs 令和 アニソン歌合戦
AZKi 8th Birthday Live Crossover: Heisei vs. Reiwa Anime Song Battle
新衣装お披露目 / 重大告知あり
New Outfit Reveal / Major Announcement Included